(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
#hololivefesEXPO24_DAY1
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
Attention
ご来場のお客様へ
For Visitors
演出の都合上
照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights
during the performance.
声出し応援 OK です
Cheering loudly is OK.
Attention
For Visitors
Please be aware of flashing lights
during the performance.
Cheering loudly is OK.
hololive 5th fes. Capture the Moment
オフィシャルグッズ
Official Goods
hololive SUPER EXPO 2024 & hololive 5th fes.
オフィシャルグッズ販売期間
Official Goods Sales Period
Attention
ご来場のお客様へ
演出の都合上 照明の点滅にご注意ください
声出し応援 OK です
Attention
For Visitors
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
Cheering loudly is ok.
Attention
For Visitors
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
Cheering loudly is ok.
バンダイキャンディ！
Bandai Candy!
ホロライブプロダクション ウエハース
hololive production wafers
BANDAI Candy
BANDAI SPIRITSより、EXPO会場でも展示中の商品をご紹介！
From BANDAI SPIRITS, introducing products also on display at the EXPO venue!
ウエハースや一番くじなど、たくさんの商品が発売いたします！
Wafers, Ichiban Kuji, and many other products will be released!
バンダイブース、BANDAI SPIRITSブースでは、会場限定グッズも数量限定配布中！
At the Bandai booth and BANDAI SPIRITS booth, venue-exclusive goods are also being distributed in limited quantities!
プレバンではすぐに使える期間限定クーポンがもらえるチャンス！
A chance to get limited-time coupons that can be used immediately at Pre-Ban!
バンダイ！
Bandai!
ヴァイスシュヴァルツ！
Weiss Schwarz!
楽しむ準備はいい？
Are you ready to have fun?
ヴァイスシュヴァルツの舞台でも、青春しよう。
Let's have a youth on the stage of Weiss Schwarz too.
プレミアムブースター ホロライブプロダクション サマーコレクション、3月22日金曜日発売！
Premium Booster hololive production Summer Collection, released on Friday, March 22nd!
ブシロード！
Bushiroad!
ホロスターズが、ヴァイスシュヴァルツブラウに登場！
HOLOSTARS appear in Weiss Schwarz Blau!
ようこそ、カードゲームの舞台へ。
Welcome to the stage of card games.
スタートデッキ&ブースターパック、ホロスターズ、好評発売中！
Start Deck & Booster Pack, HOLOSTARS, now on sale!
ブシロード！
Bushiroad!
ホロライブスーパーエキスポ2024開催を記念して、ホロライブメンバーのねんどろいどが、新衣装になって再登場！
To celebrate hololive SUPER EXPO 2024, hololive Nendoroids reappear in new outfits!
新しいねんどろいどをお楽しみに！
Look forward to the new Nendoroids!
フリューから「ホロライブ」プライズが、全国アミューズメント施設に！
hololive prizes from FuRyu are coming to amusement facilities nationwide!
2024年7月以降に続々登場！
Appearing one after another from July 2024!
今後国内のホロライブメンバー全員展開予定！
Planning to roll out all domestic hololive members in the future!
最新情報は、「キャラ広場 ホロライブ」で検索！
For the latest information, search for "Chara-Hiroba hololive"!
フリュー！
FuRyu!
Capture The Moment
hololive 5th fes. Capture the Moment
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
Attention: For Visitors
演出の都合上 照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援 OK です
Cheering loudly is OK.
※マスクの着用はお客様の任意でお願いいたします
*Mask wearing is at the visitor's discretion.
hololive 5th fes. Capture the Moment オフィシャルグッズ
hololive 5th fes. Capture the Moment Official Goods
オフィシャルグッズ販売期間
Official Goods Sales Period
バンダイ、バンダイスピリッツより、
From Bandai and Bandai Spirits,
EXPO会場でも展示中の商品をご紹介。
we're introducing products currently on display at the EXPO venue.
ガシャポンや一番くじなど、たくさんの商品が発売いたします。
Gashapon, Ichiban Kuji, and many other products are now on sale.
バンダイブース、BANDAI SPIRITSブースでは、会場限定グッズも無料配布中！
At the Bandai and BANDAI SPIRITS booths, venue-exclusive goods are being distributed for free!
プレバンではすぐに使えるクーポンもらえる！
On Premium Bandai, you can get coupons that can be used immediately!
ヴァイスシュヴァルツ！楽しむ準備はいい？
Weiß Schwarz! Are you ready to have fun?
ヴァイスシュヴァルツの舞台でも、青春しよ！
Let's enjoy our youth on the stage of Weiß Schwarz too!
プレミアムブースター ホロライブプロダクション サマーコレクション 3月22日発売！
Premium Booster: Hololive Production Summer Collection. On sale March 22nd!
ホロスターズがヴァイスシュヴァルツブラウに登場！
Holostars appears in Weiß Schwarz Blau!
ようこそ、カードゲームの舞台へ。
Welcome to the stage of card games.
スタートデッキ＆ブースターパック「ホロスターズ」好評発売中！
Start Deck & Booster Pack 'Holostars' now on sale!
hololive SUPER EXPO 2024開催を記念して、
Commemorating the holding of hololive SUPER EXPO 2024,
ホロライブメンバーのねんどろいどが、新衣装になって再登場！
Nendoroids of Hololive members return in new outfits!
新しいねんどろいどもお楽しみに！
Look forward to the new Nendoroids!
フリューから「ホロライブ」プライズが全国アミューズメント施設に、2024年7月以降に続々登場！
Hololive prizes from FuRyu will appear one after another in amusement facilities nationwide from July 2024 onwards!
今後国内のホロライブメンバー全員展開予定！
Planned to expand to all domestic Hololive members in the future!
推しの曲、めっちゃいいね！
My favorite's song is so good!
みるハコチャーン！
Miruhako-chan!
みるハコなら、臨場感たっぷりで推しのコンテンツが楽しめる！
With Miruhako, you can enjoy your favorite's content with plenty of presence!
みるハコ最高！推し事増やそう！
Miruhako is the best! Let's increase our fan activities!
hololive 5th fes. Capture the Moment
みんなの笑顔の架け橋になりますように
May I be a bridge for everyone's smiles
全力で楽しんでいきましょう！
Let's enjoy this with everything we've got!
最高の思い出を一緒に作りましょう！
Let's make the best memories together!
hololive 5th fes. Capture the Moment
hololive stage1 DAY1
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
Attention: To our visitors
演出の都合上 照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援 OK です
Cheering loudly is OK.
※マスクの着用はお客様の判断でお願いいたします
*You are free to wear a mask during the show.
Attention For Visitors
オフィシャルグッズ
Official Goods
オフィシャルグッズ販売期間
Official Goods Sales Period
Capture the Moment
hololive 5th fes. を応援しています！
Supporting hololive 5th fes.!
最高のステージになりますように！！
Wishing for the best stage ever!!
5th fes. 開催おめでとうございます！！
Congratulations on the 5th fes.!!
全力で応援します！！
I'll support you with all my might!!
最高のステージを楽しみにしてます！
Looking forward to the best stage!
最高の思い出を一緒に作りましょう！
Let's make the best memories together!
Capture the Moment
最高のライブを楽しみにしています！！
Looking forward to an amazing concert!!
hololive stage1
hololive 5th fes. Capture the Moment
Supported by Bushiroad
Official Hashtag #hololivefesEXPO24_DAY1
The concert will be starting soon.
Attention
ご来場のお客様へ
演出の都合上 照明の点滅にご注意ください
声出し応援 OK です
Attention
For Visitors
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
Cheering loudly is OK.
Attention
For Visitors
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
Cheering loudly is OK.
*You are free to wear a mask during the show.
hololive 5th fes. Capture the Moment
オフィシャルグッズ
Official Goods
hololive SUPER EXPO 2024 & hololive 5th fes.
オフィシャルグッズ販売期間
当日販売 / 事後通販
hololive SUPER EXPO 2024 & hololive 5th fes.
Official Goods Sales Period
On-site Sales / Post-event Online Sales
hololive 5th fes. Capture the Moment
Always worth flying in to see our shark-idol shine and wag her tail on stage!
5th fes 開催おめでとうございます！ 全てに感謝して 全力で楽しませていただきます！
Congratulations on the 5th fes! I'm grateful for everything and will enjoy it with all my heart!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
おい！ おい！ おい！ おい！
Oi! Oi! Oi! Oi!
アキ・ローゼンタール
Aki Rosenthal
夏色まつり
Natsuiro Matsuri
癒月ちょこ
Yuzuki Choco
戌神ころね
Inugami Korone
白銀ノエル
Shirogane Noel
宝鐘マリン
Houshou Marine
天音かなた
Amane Kanata
獅白ぼたん
Shishiro Botan
博衣こより
Hakui Koyori
沙花叉クロヱ
Sakamata Chloe
アユンダ・リス
Ayunda Risu
アイラニ・イオフィフティーン
Airani Iofifteen
パヴォリア・レイネ
Pavolia Reine
小鳥遊キアラ
Takanashi Kiara
一伊那尓栖
Ninomae Ina'nis
がうる・ぐら
Gawr Gura
ハコス・ベールズ
Hakos Baelz
パレード、パレード、パレード！
Parade, Parade, Parade!
輝くんだよ
We're gonna shine
呼び合う声を合図に
With our calling voices as a signal
パレード、パレード、パレード！
Parade, Parade, Parade!
探しに行く
Let's go and search
歌えば何度だって
No matter how many times we sing
ひとりごと 映った
A monologue was reflected
ただ 始まりだけ 信じた
I just believed in the beginning
遠く 暗がりに 灯った
It lit up far away in the darkness
それは 眩しすぎた 名前
That name was too dazzling
それは 優しすぎる 微笑み
That smile was too kind
もっと 近づきたくて 手を伸ばした
I reached out, wanting to get closer
思い出が 全部 擦り合った
All our memories rubbed together
ほら 今 迷い子は僕らになった
Look, now we've become lost children
パレード、パレード、パレード！
Parade, Parade, Parade!
輝くんだよ
We're gonna shine
悔しさも 愛おしさも
The frustration and the preciousness
脱ぎ捨てて おいで
Strip them off and come
風 夢 羽 飛び抜けろ今
Wind, dreams, wings - fly through them now
鮮やかな 祈りは 最大
Vivid prayers are at their peak
終わりなき 兆し
An endless sign
君を見つけたこと 胸を張れるよ
I can be proud of finding you
ここから これから
From here, from now on
パレード、パレード！
Parade, Parade!
頼りない予感でも　いいよ
Even if it's an unreliable premonition, it's fine
歌おう　恥ずかしくなんてないよ
Let's sing, it's not embarrassing at all
誰も解けない　ミステリー
A mystery no one can solve
いつかまた会える　ミステリー
A mystery where we can meet again someday
あの日　ゼロに始まった　ストーリー
The story that started at zero that day
数え切れない心は　数えるような想いじゃないさ
Countless hearts are more than just countable feelings
ほら今　僕らも　一つと呼ぼう
Look, now let's call us one as well
Parade Parade Parade 移りゆく今よ
Parade Parade Parade, the changing present
許し合える世界が　夜を煌めく
A world where we can forgive each other shines through the night
Parade Parade Parade まだじゃないから
Parade Parade Parade, it's not over yet
お騒がせ旅人は　君と歩くのさ
The rowdy travelers walk together with you
君と在ることなんだ
It's all about being with you
高い声を聞けば
When I hear that high-pitched voice
「おかえり」って叫ぶよ
I'll shout "Welcome home!"
当たり前じゃないか
Isn't it obvious?
Parade Parade Parade 輝くんだよ
Parade Parade Parade, keep on shining
暗がりを照らすのは　君と僕だ
The ones who light up the darkness are you and I
Parade Parade Parade 輝くんだよ
Parade Parade Parade, keep on shining
不安も愛おしさも　連れておいで
Bring along both your anxieties and your affections
果てぬ夢　晴れ　飛び出すさ
The endless dream clears up, and we'll leap out
ささやかな祈りは光　終わりなき道を
Vibrant prayers are light on an endless path
君と飛び込んで行く　素敵な舞台だ
Diving in with you, it's a wonderful stage
ここから　これから　Our Bright Parade Parade
From here, from now on, Our Bright Parade Parade
Our Bright Parade Parade
うー！
Woo!
ドキドキして　ニュ〜ッ！
Heart pounding, nyu~!
ホロフェス、行きますよー！
Holofes, here we go!
無罪！無罪！無罪！無罪！無罪！無罪！
Innocent! Innocent! Innocent! Innocent! Innocent! Innocent!
キラキラ　フラフラ
Sparkling, swaying
美少女無罪♡パイレーツ
Bishoujo Muzai♡Pirates
ねぇ、見てよ？年齢なんて関係ないってさ
Hey, look at me. Age doesn't matter, right?
そういう面倒くさいのも含めて愛してくれるって
That you'd love me including all that troublesome stuff
ねぇ、ねぇ、言ったよね？
Hey, hey, you said it, didn't you?
言ってない？フン、そういうこと言うんだ。
You didn't? Hmph, so you're gonna say that.
ちなみにこの船では美少女無罪が適用されますけど
By the way, "Beautiful Girl Innocence" is applied on this ship
混ぜて　魔法で若返り
Mix it up, becoming younger with magic
秘密の素顔は君だけ
My secret face is for you only
特別ですよ！
It's special!
あっち向いちゃ嫌よ
Don't look away
皆の者なんじゃ…
Everyone else is just...
はしゃいでないわ　近寄るまで　宝の島にして欲しい気分
I'm not frolicking. Until you get close, I want to be a treasure island
絶対！
Absolutely!
キャプテン・セーリング、ヨッシャ！
Captain sailing, yosha!
君の意志が目指した空
The sky your will aimed for
本当は自信ないけど　頑張っちゃう！
Actually, I don't have confidence, but I'll do my best!
きゅんきゅんきゅんきゅん　恋する瞳は17歳
Kyun kyun kyun kyun, eyes in love are 17 years old
全人類なっちゃえ　お友達…？
Let all of humanity become friends...?
ドキドキして　ニュ〜ッ！
Heart pounding, nyu~!
まだ早い！
It's too early!
だだだ、ダメですか？フリルの服、ちから
D-D-D, is it no good? The power of frilled clothes...
そんなことないよ！
That's not true!
だだだ、でも魔法少女になってみたい
B-B-B, but I want to try becoming a magical girl
ギリギリ有罪！
Barely guilty!
皆の御三家、いいかな？船長！
Everyone's Big Three, is it okay? Captain!
敬礼！君も本当は若い
Salute! You're actually young too
なんだって振るから　見捨てないで君たち
I'll do anything for you, so don't abandon me, you guys
ヨッシャ！いい感じ！
Yosha! Looking good!
たまに弄って　それ（でも）いいの
Occasionally tease me, that's fine too
むしろ喉の奥、本気にしちゃえ
Rather, take it seriously from the bottom of your heart
嵐の仲間
Comrades of the storm
一緒に行こう！
Let's go together!
ハートにズーム、ヨッシャ！
Zoom into the heart, yosha!
あれ、あれ？どした？メンタルさよならって言っちゃって
Wait, wait? What happened? Saying goodbye to your mental state
構ってくれる君が好き！
I like the you who pays attention to me!
きゅんきゅんきゅんきゅん　優しくしてね　17歳
Kyun kyun kyun kyun, be kind to me, 17 years old
ずっと見ててね、お楽しみ？
Keep watching forever, looking forward to it?
ドキドキして　Ah...
Heart pounding... Ah...
お許しください
Please forgive me
このマリンの
Of this Marine's...
魅力　魔力　破壊力
Charm, magic, destructive power
罪な女ね
What a sinful woman
離さないで　捕まっていて
Don't let go, hold on tight
正解のない航海を　見せつけてあげるから
I'll show you a voyage with no "correct answer"
狂わせてみたい　シビれさせたい
I want to drive you crazy, I want to make you tingle
君の一番目指して　ヨーソロー！
Aiming to be your number one, full speed ahead!
土壇場　大胆だけど　純情なの
At the last minute, I'm bold, but I'm pure-hearted
ギュッギュッギュルン　ギュッギュッギュルン
恋する準備は十分なのさ
Gyu-gyu-gyu-run, gyu-gyu-gyu-run,
I'm fully prepared to fall in love
伝説になっちゃおうよ　大人の時間
Let's become a legend, it's adult time
ドキドキして　Ah...
Heart pounding... Ah...
まだ早い
It's still too early
マリンじゃなくて　マリン船長だろ！
Not Marine, it's Captain Marine!
美少女無罪♡パイレーツ
Bishoujo Muzai♡Pirates
バーチャル・リアル越えて　「好きだ」も叫びたい
Crossing virtual and real, I want to shout "I love you"
伝えたいんだ
I want to tell you
おまつりわっしょい！
Omatsuri Wasshoi!
カモン！レッツゴー！レボ！ギボ！
サマー！カラー！フェスタ！
Come on! Let's go! Revo! Gibo!
Summer! Color! Festa!
会いたい時に　会いたい君に
忙しくてオドオドの毎日
When I want to see you, you who I want to see,
my days are busy and frantic
君に救われてるの
I'm saved by you
近い距離　不透明になった
だからもっと改まって　まつりなばい
Close distance, it's become opaque,
so liven it up more, it's Matsuri-time
限界かも　のみ込んで　コンコンコン
Might be the limit, swallowing it down, knock knock knock
混ざり合っていく感情　秒速仕掛けに
Emotions that are mixing together, in a split-second mechanism
褒め言　拾って昇天　もらってばかりだ
Picking up words of praise and ascending to heaven,
I'm always on the receiving end
注意！投げキッス　三連発
Attention! Triple blown kiss
てて　無限見てて　ついていこうぜ
Keep watching infinitely, let's go together
引き連れて　ありがとう　大好き　捧げたいんだ
Thank you for taking me along, I love you, I want to offer it to you
新年目も　誕生日も　一緒に彩ね
New Year's, birthdays, let's color them together
バーチャル・リアル越えて　「好きだ」も叫びたい
伝えたい　I love you love you
Crossing virtual and real, I want to shout "I love you",
I want to tell you, I love you love you
ハッ！
Ha!
はい、せーの！
Ready, set, go!
何何？好き好き！
What what? Love love!
一番愛してる！
I love you the most!
何何？好き好き！
What what? Love love!
一番愛してる！
I love you the most!
はい、せーの！
Ready, set, go!
思い積もり思い愛　暴走しかけて
Thinking, piling up, thinking, love, about to run wild
少し反省　改めて　今日も大好き
Reflecting a bit and starting over, I love you today too
てて　無限見てて　ついていこうぜ
Keep watching infinitely, let's go together
引き連れて　ありがとう　大好き　捧げたいんだ
Thank you for taking me along, I love you, I want to offer it to you
新年目も　誕生日も　一緒に彩ね
New Year's, birthdays, let's color them together
バーチャル・リアル越えて　「好きだ」も叫びたい
伝えたい　I love you love you
Crossing virtual and real, I want to shout "I love you",
I want to tell you, I love you love you
白化したあとのまつり
The festival after turning white
わっしょい！おまつりわっしょい！
Wasshoi! Omatsuri Wasshoi!
カモン！レッツゴー！レボ！ギボ！
サマー！カラー！フェスタ！
Come on! Let's go! Revo! Gibo!
Summer! Color! Festa!
オタ芸最高！
Otageru is the best!
ぎゅーどん どーんどん ぎゅー どん ぎゅー
Gyu-don-don-don-gyu-don-gyu
ギュッとしてどーん！
Hug me tight and BAM!
せーの、ギュッとしてどーん！
One, two, hug me tight and BAM!
大好き！ギュッとしてどーん！
I love you! Hug me tight and BAM!
おろしポン酢かけて さっぱりとハピハピ
Drizzled with grated radish and ponzu, refreshing and happy-happy
豪華に特盛りワッショイ！
(ぎゅっぎゅっぎゅっ ぎゅっぎゅっぎゅっぎゅっぎゅ)
Go big with an extra-large serving, heave-ho!
(Gyu-gyu-gyu, gyu-gyu-gyu-gyu-gyu)
つゆだく生卵 トッピングはお好み (おいしー)
Extra broth and a raw egg, toppings as you like (Delicious!)
のれんをさあくぐろう 笑顔で決めたいね
Let's pass through the shop curtain, I want to end with a smile
はい、ハラペコのバブちゃんたち こっちでちゅよー
Alright, my hungry babies, come this way!
食べる前に お姉さんと運動しまちょうね
Before we eat, let's exercise with Big Sis!
ヘイ、カモン、エブリバディ、サンナポ！
アーユーハングリー？
Hey, come on everybody, sunnapo!
Are you hungry?
ぎゅっぎゅっぎゅっ ぎゅっぎゅっぎゅっ
からの いただきまーしゅ！
Gyu-gyu-gyu, gyu-gyu-gyu,
and now... Let's eat!
さあさ ぎゅーどんだ ぎゅーどんだ 一緒に食べよう
Come on, it's beef bowl time, it's beef bowl time, let's eat together
君と仲良しハニーバニー そろそろふわわい
Being good friends with you, honey-bunny, getting light-headed soon
ほろりお肉 お肉 詰まっちゃダメー！
The melt-in-your-mouth meat, the meat, don't get choked up!
全部食べたいんだ 褒めちゃいな
なでなでよしよし ちゅっちゅっちゅ
I want to eat it all, so praise me,
there-there, good girl, kiss-kiss-kiss
せーの、ぎゅーどん！
One, two, Gyu-don!
えっ、牛丼が嫌い？ もう、なんでそういうこと言うの！
Eh, you hate beef bowls? Geez, why would you say that?!
そんな悪い子は 食べちゃうぞ！
I'll eat up bad kids like you!
好き好き大好き ラブラブラブ せーの、ぎゅー！
I like you, I like you, I love you, love-love-love, one, two, Gyu!
むちむち 責めちゃダメ ドキドキしちゃった ほっぺにちゅ
Stop picking on my squishiness, you made my heart race, kiss on the cheek
モグモグ ねぎだく (へい！) ところが全然足りません
Munch, munch, extra green onions (Hey!), but it's not enough at all
バクバク つゆだく (へい！) それでも全然足りません
Chomp, chomp, extra broth (Hey!), still not enough at all
バクバク 肉だく (あん！) まだまだ全然足りないの
Chomp, chomp, extra meat (Ahn!), it's still not enough at all
バクバク どくのくん？ (ぎゅー！) ドキがムネムネ止まらない
Chomp, chomp, pounding? (Gyu!), my heart won't stop thumping
牛丼を食べるときは お口でフーフーして... って あー！
When eating a beef bowl, blow on it first... like this, say 'Ah'!
口角がついちゃって かわいい
It got on the corner of your mouth, cute
優しく丁寧だぞ。ふふ、いい子いい子
Be gentle and careful. Hehe, good boy, good boy
お腹いっぱいになっちゃったね
You're full now, aren't you?
一緒に寝ちゃう？
Wanna sleep together?
おやすみなさーい！
Good night!
もしも君が シュンとしちゃっても
Even if you feel a bit down
ぎゅって ぎゅって ぎゅって 抱きしめてあげる
I'll give you a big, big, big hug
みんなで歌おう！
Let's all sing!
さあさ ぎゅーどんだ ぎゅーどんだ 一緒に食べよう
Come on, it's beef bowl time, it's beef bowl time, let's eat together
君と何度でもハニーバニー そろそろふわわい
With you any number of times, honey-bunny, getting light-headed soon
ほろりお肉 お肉 詰まっちゃダメー！
The melt-in-your-mouth meat, the meat, don't get choked up!
全部食べたいんだ 褒めちゃいな
なでなでよしよし ちゅっちゅっちゅ
I want to eat it all, so praise me,
there-there, good girl, kiss-kiss-kiss
せーの、ぎゅーどん！
One, two, Gyu-don!
大好き！ギュッとしてどーん！
I love you! Hug me tight and BAM!
まだまだどーん！ 銀の目覚めでもギュッとしてどーん！
More and more BAM! Even with a silver awakening, hug me tight and BAM!
ぎゅー！
Gyu!
宝鐘マリン
Houshou Marine
天音かなた
Amane Kanata
ユニット曲、1曲目は...
Unit song, the first one is...
釜ドマ！
Kamadoma!
なの節踊れば　バシッバシッ
If you dance the Nano-style... Bash! Bash!
詰め込め燃え咲け　本意開成
Stuff it in, burn bright, true intentions revealed
適当に頑張ろうぜ　そんなんでもいいけどさ
Let's just take it easy, that's fine too
必死に頑張ろうぜ　それが僕らだよな
Let's give it our all, that's who we are
土左衛門じゃねえんだわ　飛んで火にいるんじゃねえんだわ
We're not dead bodies, we're not jumping into the fire
ズンバズンババッチリ　言っちゃってる時に決まってる
Zumba, zumba, perfectly decided when we say it
カナタちゃんちょっと　ドロンしちゃおっかなって感じで
Kanata-chan, thinking of disappearing for a bit
まだまだかなまり、
KanaMari isn't over yet,
終わりはせんよ！
it's not finished!
盛り上がってけー！
Keep the excitement going!
快速ならゴーフォー　誇り咲けるよほうさあ
If you're fast, go for it! Pride can bloom
今　旗の下へ
Now, under the flag
宝鐘海賊団... 出航！
Houshou Pirates... Set sail!
踊れ阿呆に見る阿呆！
Dancing fools and watching fools!
全速前進だー！
Full speed ahead!
踊れ阿呆に見る阿呆！
Dancing fools and watching fools!
あーもー、船長は君たちをそんな子に育てた覚えはありません！
Oh jeez, the Captain doesn't remember raising you to be children like that!
本当に、ね〜だぞ！
Seriously, I really don't!
立てば芍薬、座れば牡丹、歩く姿は生身の天使！
Standing like a peony, sitting like a tree peony, walking like a living angel!
全速前進... アホイ！
Full speed ahead... Ahoy!
それじゃあ 行きますよ！
Alright, here we go!
出航ー！
Set sail!
あ、そうだ 挨拶しないと。
Oh, right. We have to do our greetings.
挨拶！ 挨拶！
Greetings! Greetings!
えっと、あ、じゃあ ちょっと考えてきたから。
Well, I've thought of something.
あのね、えっと マリンが「アホイ」って言ったら、
So, when Marine says "Ahoy,"
「アホイ」って言ってください。
please say "Ahoy" back.
こんな感じで、かなたのように。お願いします。
Just like that, follow Kanata's lead. Please.
まずはマリン色に染めよう。
First, let's dye the place in Marine's color.
あ、そうですね。せっかくですから。
Oh, you're right. Since we're here.
せっかく何でペンライト赤色でおねがいします。
Since it's a special occasion, please turn your penlights red.
おねがいします！
Please!
レッド！ レッド！ あ、きれい！
Red! Red! Oh, beautiful!
どうもありがとうございます。素敵ですよ。
Thank you very much. It looks lovely.
じゃあ 行きますよ！
Alright, here we go!
えっと、どうだったかな。アホイ！
Um, how did it go again? Ahoy!
ホロライブ3期... ちょっと待って、アホイって今言った みんな？
Hololive 3rd Gen... Wait, did you all just say "Ahoy"?
みんなアホイって今言った？ ちょっと待って マリン隙を与えなかった。
Did you all just say "Ahoy"? Wait, I didn't give you the cue.
ちょっと言って、お仕置きで。はい、アホイって言ったらアホイって言ってくださいね。
Say it as punishment. Okay, when I say "Ahoy," please say "Ahoy."
行きますよ！ アホイ！
Here we go! Ahoy!
（アホイ！）
(Ahoy!)
ああ 素敵 素敵 素敵。えー、何ですか。
Ah, wonderful, wonderful, wonderful. So, um...
ホロライブ3期生 ホウショウ海賊団 船長のホウショウマリンですぅ〜。
Hololive 3rd Gen, the Captain of the Houshou Pirates, Houshou Marine!
イェーイ！ ありがとうございます。ありがとうございます。
Yay! Thank you very much. Thank you.
素敵ですよ。ありがとうございます！ 次はかなたんだね。
It's wonderful. Thank you! Next is Kanatan.
次 行きますよ みんな。えー、ライトブルーにしてください。おねがいします。かなたの色に。
Next is me, everyone. Please turn them light blue. For my color.
あー！ ブルーじゃないよ！
Ah! Not blue!
ライトブルー！ ライトブルー！ ライトブルー。そう、ライトブルーなんですよ。
Light blue! Light blue! Light blue. Yes, it's light blue.
じゃあ 行きますよ みんな。
Alright, here we go, everyone.
こんかなたー！
Kon-Kanata!
（こんかなたー！）
(Kon-Kanata!)
キャッチコピーは握力50キロ。ギュッギュッて握り潰しちゃうぞ。
My catchphrase is "Grip strength: 50kg." I'll crush you!
ホロライブ4期生 天音かなたです。イェーイ！
Hololive 4th Gen, Amane Kanata! Yay!
わー！ ありがとうございます。わー、楽しい！
Whoa! Thank you very much. This is so fun!
楽しい、ああ楽しすぎる。え、もう何しようと思ってたんだけど もう記憶が...
So fun, ah, so much fun. Um, I forgot what I was going to do next...
ね！ もうなんか胸がいっぱいで今 混乱中です。いや、やばい。
Right! My heart is so full, I'm just confused right now. Wow.
まず楽曲の話します？ そうしましょうか。
Should we talk about the song first? Let's do that.
皆さん どうでしたか？ 二人のね、マッシュアップでしたよ！
How was it, everyone? It was a mashup of our two songs!
そうなんです。え、ちょっとこの曲になった経緯とか...
That's right. About how we decided on this song...
せっかく「特バン！ ドラダ」で、あのマリンの「アホイ」はやっぱり、
Since it's "Special Bandorada," and Marine's "Ahoy" has that...
コールアンドレスポンスはね、すごく素敵な曲なので。
great call-and-response, it's such a wonderful song.
そうなんです。これ両方できたらな... と思ったんです。
Exactly. I thought it'd be great if we could do both.
でもさ、やっぱライブとなるとさ、やっぱ新曲やりたいじゃん？
But you know, when it comes to a live, you want to do a new song, right?
そうそうそう。でもさ、1曲目のオリ曲 歌いたいじゃん？
Right, right. But you also want to sing your first original song, right?
歌いたいよね！
We do!
両方やっちゃえみたいな 1曲目。
So we thought, let's just do both for the first song.
楽しかったですかー！
Did you have fun?!
（イェーイ！）ありがとうございます！ ありがとうございます。
(Yay!) Thank you very much! Thank you.
素敵ですよ。はい、はい。
It's wonderful. Yes, yes.
ということでね、この 僕たちの「ふぅ〜」という感じはですね、
And so, as we catch our breath like this...
あの 韓国 インドネシアでライブビューイングを行っているということで。
we're also having a live viewing in Korea and Indonesia.
そうなんです！ 見てるかみんな？
That's right! Are you guys watching?
韓国の皆さん！ インドネシアの皆さん！
Everyone in Korea! Everyone in Indonesia!
ハロー、イェーイ！
Hello, yay!
イェーイ！ みんな見ているということでね、
Yay! Since everyone is watching,
ぜひぜひライブの感想を、ハッシュタグ「ホロライブフェスエキスポアンダーバーデイワン」で、
please share your thoughts on the live with the hashtag #hololivefesEXPO_DAY1
SNSにアップしてください！
on social media!
おねがいします！ オッケー、オッケー。
Please! Okay, okay.
でもさ、せっかく皆さんいらっしゃいますから、なんかやる？
But since everyone is here, shall we do something?
やる？ ちょっと波作っちゃう？
Do something? Like making a wave?
え、いきなり作っちゃう？ ちょっと待って 一旦さ、
Oh, a wave already? Wait, how about we do...
あれやる？ 男の子、女の子みたいな。
that first? The "Boys and Girls" thing.
それだ！ それだ！ じゃあ みんな行くよ。
That's it! That's it! Alright, here we go, everyone.
男の子ー！
Boys!
（イェーイ！）
(Yay!)
うわ、かっこいい！ キャーかっこいい！
Whoa, so cool! Kyah, so cool!
じゃあ 行くよ。女の子少ないかもしれないから、
Alright, here we go. There might be few girls,
頑張ってデカい声出してね。おっきい声出してね。
so please try your best to shout loudly.
行くよ、女の子ー！
Here we go, girls!
（イェーイ！）
(Yay!)
うわー！ 綺麗な声が！ 女いる！ 見えてるよ！
Whoa! Such pretty voices! There are girls! We see you!
ありがとう！ ありがとう！ 嬉しいです。
Thank you! Thank you! I'm so happy.
両方行こう、両方。あ、そうね。
Let's do both, both. Ah, right.
せーの！
One, two...
どっちもー！ どっちもー！
Everyone! Everyone!
（イェーイ！）わー！ ありがとう！
(Yay!) Whoa! Thank you!
楽し、楽しですよ。
It's fun, it's fun!
あ、波作る？
Oh, shall we make a wave?
波作ろう波作ろう波作ろう。
Let's make a wave! Wave, wave!
え、ゆっくり行こうゆっくり。こっちから行こうこっちから。
Uh, let's go slowly, slowly. Start from this side.
みんな怪我しないようにね。
Everyone, make sure not to get hurt.
マジ波作んないか？
Seriously, let's make a wave.
いける？波作れる？
Ready? Can you guys make a wave?
さあ、行くよ！
Alright, here we go!
ゆっくり行こうゆっくり。
Let's go slowly, slowly.
せーの！はぁああああああああ！
Ready, set... Gooooooooo!
綺麗綺麗綺麗！
Beautiful, beautiful, beautiful!
すごーい！綺麗よー、いいよー！
Amazing! It looks beautiful, so good!
逆行くよ、逆行くよ！
Going the other way, other way!
せーの！はぁああああああ！
Ready, set... Gooooooooo!
みんな！
Everyone!
綺麗！すごーい！ありがとうございます！
So beautiful! Amazing! Thank you so much!
すごい綺麗！
So incredibly beautiful!
うわー！
Whoa!
上手！みんな上手上手！
Great job! You're all so good!
あったかい、最高！
It's so heartwarming, the best!
わぁ感動！
Wow, I'm moved!
お前らありがとう！
Thank you guys!
さあ、はい。
Now then...
かなたちゃん。
Kanata-chan.
はい。
Yes?
そして皆さん。
And everyone.
はい。
Yes?
ここで重大なお知らせがあります。
I have an important announcement to make here.
なによ？
What is it?
なんと、無料パートは...
Believe it or not, the free part...
はっ。
Huh?
ここまでです！
...ends here!
無料パートぉおおお！？嘘だぁあああ！ええええ！？
The free part?! No way! What?!
概要欄からチケットの購入お願いします！
Please purchase tickets through the link in the description!
お願いします、お願いします、よろしくお願いします、お願いします、お願いします。
Please! Please do! Please!
やっちゃう？
Shall we do it?
やっちゃおうか。
Let's do it.
ま、最初パッて出てきたし僕たち。
Well, we did just burst onto the scene.
それでは、まだまだここからね、あるのでね。
Well, there's still more to come after this, you know.
ちょっとかなまりね、最初の登場のポーズでもう一回。
So Kanata and Marine will do our opening pose one more time.
あ、そうですね、終わりたいと思います。
Oh, that's right. Let's finish with that.
まだまだ続くから、みんな楽しんでくださいね。
It's still going on, so everyone, please enjoy!
楽しんでー！
Have fun!
はーい！バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
さあ、行くよ。
Okay, here we go.
うん。
Yeah.
せーの！
Ready, set...
Capture the Moment!
無料パートは終了いたしました！
ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The free part has ended!
Thank you for watching!
無料パートは終了いたしました！
ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The free part has ended.
Thank you for watching!